In many scientific fields such as bioinformatics, medical imaging, and
バイオインフォマティクス、医療用画像、天文学など多くの科学分野で、
astronomy large quantities of data need to be
大量のデータを分析する必要があります。
analyzed. This can involve large-scale and repetitive processes in long
データ分析では、
pipelines of different tools — referred to as workflows. It can be very
ワークフローと呼ばれる複数のツールからなるパイプライン処理を大規模なデータに対して反復的に実行することがあります。
time-consuming to run data for all these different tools by hand and convert
データに対して異なるツールを手作業で実行することや、 各ツールの出力を次のツールの入力形式に変換する作業は、
outputs to various formats to make them compatible with the next step.
非常に時間がかかる作業です。
Workflow management systems are designed to alleviate this problem by allowing
ワークフロー管理システムは、ワークフローを形式的に表現し、
these workflows to be expressed formally and providing infrastructure to set up.
ワークフローのセットアップ、実行、監視を行うことで、これらの問題を軽減します。
execute, and monitor them. This formal expression of workflows allows for
ワークフローを形式的に表現することで、研究者の間でワークフローを共有、
scientists to easily share and reuse them. Crucially they can also be used to
再利用することが簡単になります。 さらに、この形式化されたワークフローは、
verify results of computation for published work. However there are many
論文で発表された計算結果の検証にも使用できます。
competing [ways] for describing workflows which is a barrier to this aim.
しかしワークフローを記述する表現方法は数多くあるため、この目的は達成できていません。
Currently there are over a hundred different data analysis workflow systems
現在、数百種類以上のデータ解析ワークフローシステムがありますが、
with no interoperability between them. The need has arisen to have a single
それらの間には相互運用性がありません。
common standard and so the "Common Workflow Language" project was created: an
単一の共通の規格が必要なため、「Common Workflow Language」プロジェクトが始まりました：
open standard designed to express workflows and their tooling in groups of
Common Workflow Language は、 YAML フォーマットのファイル群で
YAML structured text files.
ワークフローとツールを表現するオープンな規格です。